<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- SudoQ is a Sudoku-App for Adroid Devices with Version 2.2 at least. -->
<!-- Copyright (C) 2012  Haiko Klare, Julian Geppert, Jan-Bernhard Kordaß, Jonathan Kieling, Tim Zeitz, Timo Abele -->
<!-- This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.  -->
<!-- This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.  -->
<resources>
    <!-- Sudoku Tutorial -->
    <string name="sf_tutorial_sudoku_title">Sudoku</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_sudoku_description1">A sudoku is a logic-based, combinatorial number-placement puzzle. The original sudoku
	    is a 9x9 grid that has to be filled with digits so hat each column, each row and each of the nine 3x3 sub-grids contains
	    all the digits from 1 to 9. At the beginning a sudoku is partially completed and has only one correct solution.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_sudoku_description2">Further sudoku types do not define the 3x3 sub-grids but other sets of fields which are 
	    represented by a black edging or gray shaded fields in this app. The following images show both types of representation which can 
	    overlap:</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_sudoku_squiggly">Squiggly Type A Sudoku</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_sudoku_xsudoku">X-Sudoku Type</string>
    
	<!-- Assistances Tutorial -->
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_title">Assistances</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_description1">There are several assistances available to make it easier to solve a sudoku.
	    These assistances can be classified as "passive" and "active" assistances.</string>
	<string name = "sf_tutorial_assistances_description2">But: Activating a passive assistance or using an active assistance implies 
	    your highscore to be lowered. Using an assistance has an effect on the highscore equal to needing more time to solve the
	    sudoku, so the assistances are presented as additional needed time behind the game time itself.</string>
	 
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_title">Passive assistances</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_description1">Passive assistances are those that can be activated in the profile or before
	    starting a game. These assistances do not have to be called in a game but therefore they cannot be activated or deactivated in the
	    game.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_markrowcolumn_title">Mark row / column</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_markrowcolumn_description1">Activating this assistance emphasises the fields in the
	    currently selected row and column.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_autoadjustnotes_title">Auto adjust notes</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_autoadjustnotes_description1">This assistance updates your notes when a digit is put into a field. 
	    If that digit is in the notes of a field in the same row, column or block you put it in, it is removed from those notes. </string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_markwrongsymbols_title">Mark wrong symbols</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_markwrongsymbols_description1">If a digit is put into a field although it is already 
	    in a field of the same row, column or block it is marked red because there cannot be the same digit in both fields.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_inputassistance_title">Input assistance</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_passive_inputassistance_description1">With this assistance activated you can only put a digit into a
	    field that is not in one of the fields of the same row, column or block yet. All other digits are grayed out.</string>
	
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_title">Active assistances</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_description1">Active assistances can be used as you need them during a game.
	    You can reach them by clicking on the button shown left.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_solverandomfield_title">Solve random field</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_solverandomfield_description1">A random field is automatically solved for you.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_solvecurrentfield_title">Solve current field</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_solvecurrentfield_description1">The field you have currently selected is solved for you.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_check_title">Check solution</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_check_description1">Your current solution is checked and a message tells you if your
	    currently solved fields are all correct or if there is a field that is solved wrong.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_backtolastcorrect_title">Back to last correct status</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_backtolastcorrect_description1">Using this assistance reverts the game to the last state
	    where all fields you have solved were correct. Although all your action that are reverted are saved in the action history and can
	    be redone.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_surrender_title">Surrender</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_assistances_active_surrender_description1">This is not an ordinary assistance. Using this the whole sudoku
	    is automatically solved and you can take a look at the solution. You will get no score for a game you surrendered.</string>
	    
	<!-- ActionTree Tutorial -->
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_title">Action History</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_description1">The action history saves everything you do in a sudoku game. Every field you modify by either
	    solving it or by setting notes is saved into an action history. This enables you to try a solution and go back if it was
	    wrong without having to memorise every step you made since your solution was right for the last time.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_description2">With the button at the left you can open this history in a game and navigate through the
	    actions you did.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_description3">If you move back in the history and start playing from there a new branch is the history
	    is created, so you can even go back to your old solution again.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_state">The image on the left shows a single action you did in the history.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_bookmark">In the action history you can set bookmarks to remember a state. Such a bookmark is represented
	    as you can see in the image on the left.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_current_state">The image on the left shows how the state you are currently in is marked.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_branching">If there is a state from which you tried two different solutions there are two branches and
	    the state is marked as you can see on the left.</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_redoundo_title">Undo / Redo</string>
	<string name="sf_tutorial_action_redoundo_description">With the buttons on the left you can easily undo or redo an action without
	    opening the action history.</string>
</resources>